Cindy Edington

3063 Portsmouth Avenue, Cincinnati, OH 45208 linkedin.com/in/cindyedington cindyedington@gmail.com

650.305.0305

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Analytical and creative thinker excited to use my Java development skills to build great products. Former marketing manager who conceptualized and executed numerous highly visible customer education programs during my four years at Google. Lifelong learner and self-starter who is comfortable forging a path within a fast paced, rapidly scaling organization.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS

- Eclipse
- PostgreSQL
- JQuery
- JUnit/TDD

EDUCATION:

Tech Elevator, Cincinnati, OH October 2017 - Present Student, Java Development

- Participated in 14 week Java coding boot camp learning how to develop dynamic web based software systems using the Java programming language
- Developed Vending Machine Software in Java using OOP fundamentals, CLI, and file I/O
- Wrote reservation system for a National Park Campground utilizing Java, CLI and PostgreSQL

Web Courses / Independent Coursework 2017 - Present

Introduction to Python for Data Science, DataCamp Introduction to R, DataCamp Introduction to Probability and Data - Labs, DataCamp HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery at FreeCodeCamp

Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA BA in Sociology and BA in Spanish

Graduated with Honors, Sociology Departmental Honors, 5-Time Dean's List Fluent in Spanish

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Google, Mountain View, CA Industry Marketing Manager

2009 - 2005 March 2007 - May 2009

Promoted to NABM Marketing Team

 Launched the Google Marketer's Playbook series at various industry conferences, including four ad:tech events and SMX Santa Clara where we educated advertisers and agencies on different aspects of Google Business Solutions. Reached over 150 advertisers at each event and tracked event satisfaction and likelihood to use product. Leveraged our content to reach over 20,000 views on YouTube

- Developed and managed a complex yearly events and conference budget of \$500K, executing over 12 unique education and appreciation events for the OSO AdWords top-tier advertisers including Google Zeitgeist luncheon and AdWords client forums; partnered with sales finance to create a code-based system to verticalize budget requests and spend
- Partnered with corporate communications to create and streamline a industry conference speaker request for OSO AdWords sales managers
- Conceptualized, developed collateral and executed the first on campus Vertical and Industry Summit for 440 CSRs consisting of 95+ different educational seminars; 80% found it to be very or extremely valuable for newly verticalized sales teams
- Launched the AdWords Step by Step book to over 2,500 new advertisers to educate on search engine marketing with Google; over 90% felt it was useful or very useful
- Designed, managed and launched industry training for 300+ OSO AdWords Account Managers; partnered with the AdSense team to repurpose the training
- Managed the AdWords Seminars for Success program which educated advertisers in over 25 events, providing a scalable educational model for our tail-end customers
- Executed multiple AdWords API days and the first ever National Agency Advisory Council in both east and west coast locations, producing valuable feedback and relationship building for our sales teams, product managers and engineers

AdWords Associate, National Agency Team

June 2006 - March 2007

Promoted to a Dedicated Account Manager

- Managed five different online advertising agencies and end clients, including product support, customer education and cross-sales initiatives; represented the needs of online agencies to internal teams such as product specialists, marketing and sales management
- Created a pre-brief process for beta changes as well as account optimization training for OSO agencies
- Coordinated the Google Advertising Professionals certification and customer support queue
- Successfully organized and executed OSO AdWords' first ever national agency appreciation event attended by OSO Account Managers and Directors

AdWords Coordinator

April 2005 - June 2006

Hired full time and also promoted one level after four months in the temporary program

- Provided excellent customer service to all advertisers with AdWords accounts including optimization, education and problem resolution
- Answered advertisers questions via email and phone with focus on education and upselling
- Reviewed quality of AdWords team members outgoing email correspondence and provided feedback to ensure excellent customer service

AdWords Representative

January 2005 - April 2005

- Approved or disapproved advertisements for Google based on policy guidelines
- Reviewed Google Advertising Professional Modules' new quiz questions for grammar and inconsistencies

Honors and Awards at Google:

Online Sales and Operations Vice President Award by David Fischer, 2-time OSO Gold Award winner, 2-time AdWords MVP Nominee